(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
今日ほアイドル! First Anniversary 3D LIVE
Idol Today! First Anniversary 3D LIVE
スペシャルゲストあり!
With special guests!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
作詞・作曲:BETTI
Happy Synthesizer
Lyrics/Composition: BETTI
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, I'll play a melody
that will reach the depths of your heart.
はかなく散った淡い片思い
笑い話だね 今となれば
A fleeting, faint unrequited love,
it's just a funny story now.
見るもの全て輝いて見えた
あの日々がキレイに笑ってるよ
Everything I saw seemed to sparkle,
those days are smiling beautifully.
我慢する事だけ覚えなきゃいけないの？
「大人になって頂戴ね？」ならなくていいよ
Do I have to learn only how to endure?
"Please grow up, okay?" You don't have to.
知らない事ばかり知らないなんて言えなくて
「大変お似合いで」嘘ついてゴメンね
So many things I don't know, I couldn't say I didn't know,
"They suit you perfectly," sorry for lying.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, I'll play a melody
that will reach the depths of your heart.
つまらない「たてまえ」やヤな事全部
消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase all the boring "face-saving" and
unpleasant things with this sound.
何の取り柄もない僕にたった一つ
少しだけ出来ることが
For someone like me with no saving grace,
there's just one thing I can do a little.
心躍らせる飾らない言葉
電子音で伝えるよ
Sending heart-dancing, unadorned words
through electronic sounds.
好きになる理由 理屈なんかじゃなくて
こじつけなんていらないんじゃない？
The reason for falling in love isn't logic,
so we don't need justifications, do we?
時代のせいと諦めたらそこまで
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
If you give up and blame it on the times, that's where it ends,
nothing starts unless you take a step.
ゴメンね夜遅く寝るところだったでしょ？
驚いた私もかけようとしてた
Sorry it's late, you were about to sleep, weren't you?
Surprised, I was about to call you too.
心の裏側をくすぐられてるような
惹かれ合う二人に幸せな音を
Like the back of my heart is being tickled,
a happy sound for two people drawn to each other.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see, it's getting fun,
I'll play a melody that wipes away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
自分に素直になればいい
It's okay not to act tough, isn't it?
Just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない僕にたった一つ
少しだけ出来ること
For someone like me with no saving grace,
there's just one thing I can do a little.
ちょっと照れるような単純な気持ち
電子音で伝えるよ
Sending slightly embarrassing, simple feelings
through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, I'll play a melody
that will reach the depths of your heart.
つまらない「たてまえ」やヤな事全部
消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase all the boring "face-saving" and
unpleasant things with this sound.
何の取り柄もない僕にたった一つ
少しだけ出来ることが
For someone like me with no saving grace,
there's just one thing I can do a little.
心躍らせる飾らない言葉
電子音で伝えるよ
Sending heart-dancing, unadorned words
through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see, it's getting fun,
I'll play a melody that wipes away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？別に
自分に素直になればいい
It's okay not to act tough, isn't it?
Just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない僕にたった一つ
少しだけ出来ること
For someone like me with no saving grace,
there's just one thing I can do a little.
ちょっと照れるような単純な気持ち
電子音で伝えるよ
Sending slightly embarrassing, simple feelings
through electronic sounds.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ららいおん！
Lala-ion!
ということで、
And so,
ホロライブ五期生、獅白ぼたんでーす！
I'm Hololive 5th gen, Shishiro Botan!
今日は一周年記念でちょっとね、特別に「今日はアイドル」っていうテーマで
Today is my first anniversary, so as a special treat, with the theme "Today I'm an Idol",
珍しく獅白ぼたんとしては珍しく歌メインの配信となっております。
This is an unusual music-focused stream for me, Shishiro Botan.
で、まあソロ曲ね、今歌ったんですけど。やっぱいろんな歌を歌いたいっていうことで
And well, I just sang my solo song, but I want to sing all kinds of songs.
なんかデュエット曲とかもゲストさんを呼んで歌いたいなってちょっと色々考えていたんですね。
So I was thinking about inviting guests to sing duets and stuff.
なので…ん？
Therefore... hmm?
ん？なんかいたかな？
Hmm? Was someone there?
えっと、ゲストのね、方を呼んで、いろんな曲をちょっと歌っていくっていう時間も設けたいなと思っております。
Um, I'd like to set aside some time to invite guests and sing various songs together.
ということで…
And so...
あら！出た出た！
Oh! There she is!
見つかった見つかった！
Found her, found her!
ということで今日の1人目のゲストです！
And so, here is today's first guest!
戌神ころねと申しまーす！わー！
I'm Inugami Korone! Yay!
よろしくお願いしまーす！ころね先輩！
Glad to be here! Korone-senpai!
ぼたんちゃん一周年おめでとう！
Botan-chan, happy first anniversary!
ありがとうございます！一周年だ！
Thank you! It's been a year!
ということで、お楽しい時間だった。
So, it's been a fun time.
はい、ありがとうございました。
Yes, thank you very much.
またね。あんっ…
See you later. Oof...
おいおいおいおい！
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
まだ、まだある感じ、まだある感じ。まだ、まだ、まだ。
There's more, there's more. Wait, wait, wait.
今日はね！アイドル！っていうことで！
Today is about being an idol!
あ！忘れかけていたことだ。
Ah! I almost forgot.
ころね先輩にもアイドルをしていただき…
I'd like Korone-senpai to be an idol too...
一緒に？ホント？あ、でももうアイドルしてるね。
Together? Really? But I'm already an idol.
してるでしょ！
You are!
うおー！すごい！一緒にアイドルできるの？
Whoa! Amazing! We can be idols together?
そう、だからね、今日はちょっところね先輩と歌いたい曲を…
That's right, so today, I have a song I want to sing with Korone-senpai...
はっ！用意してきたので、歌っていただけると大変嬉しいです。
Ah! I've prepared one, so I'd be very happy if you'd sing it with me.
何かな何かな？
What could it be?
じゃあもう早速いきます？
Shall we get right to it?
行こう！
Let's go!
はい。わかりました。じゃあタイトルコールいきますよ！
Alright, understood. Then, let's do the title call!
「DANZEN! ふたりは プリキュア」！ Ver.Max Heart！
“DANZEN! Futari wa PreCure”! Ver. Max Heart!
Max Heart!
プリキュア プリキュア
PreCure, PreCure
DANZEN!ふたりはプリキュア ver.Max Heart
作詞 青木久美子 作曲 小杉保夫
DANZEN! Futari wa PreCure ver. Max Heart
Lyrics: Kumiko Aoki, Composition: Yasuo Kosugi
DANZEN! ふたりは プリキュア Ver.Max Heart
DANZEN! Futari wa PreCure Ver. Max Heart
プリティで キュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア
Pretty and Cure-Cure, we are PreCure
一難去って また一難 ぶっちゃけありえない
One trouble after another, it's totally unbelievable
制服着てても ふたりは むちゃくちゃタフだし
Even in school uniforms, we're super tough
お互いピンチを 乗り越えるたび
Every time we overcome a pinch together
強く 強く 自覚 自覚 なるね
We become strongly, strongly aware of it
Max Heart!
Yeah! 呼べばMy Best 生きてるんだから 失敗なんて めっちゃない
Yeah! If you call, My Best, since we're alive, failure's not even a thing
笑う門に 福来たるでしょ ネガティブだって ぶっ飛ばす
Fortune comes to those who laugh, right? We'll blow away the negatives
命の花 咲かせて思い切り もっとバリバリ
Let the flowers of life bloom with all our might, even more full of energy
プリキュア プリキュア
PreCure, PreCure
プリティで キュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア
Pretty and Cure-Cure, we are PreCure
たまには放課後 ホッとおしゃべりベリータイム
Sometimes after school, a relaxing tea-and-chat time
噂は恋する乙女の ビタミン剤だもん
Rumors are the vitamins of girls in love
闇夜に浮かんだ 虹の架け橋
A rainbow bridge floating in the dark night
ここに ここに 降りて 降りて 奇跡
A miracle descending, descending right here
Yeah! 呼べばMy Best 全力なんだから 友情愛情 最高潮
Yeah! If you call, My Best, since we're giving it our all, friendship and love at their peak
論より証拠 輝くえくぼ 必殺技で ハート射抜く
Proof over argument, a shining dimple, piercing the heart with a special move
瞳に星 映して思い切り もっとキラキラ
Reflecting stars in our eyes with all our might, even more sparkly
プリキュア プリキュア
PreCure, PreCure
プリティで キュアキュア ふたりは プリキュア
Pretty and Cure-Cure, we are PreCure
プリキュア プリキュア
PreCure, PreCure
よーし後半行くよ！行きます！
Alright, here comes the second half! Let's go!
プリキュア プリキュア
PreCure, PreCure
明日は明日の 風吹く マジ意味わかんない
Tomorrow is another day, I really don't get it
今しかできない 宿題 頑張らなくちゃ
Homework I can only do now, I've got to work hard
真逆のキャラでも...
Even with opposite personalities...
...あいつ通じてる
...we understand each other.
夢は
Dreams...
夢を
...dreams...
生きる
...living...
力マックスパワー！
...Power, Max Power!
イェイ！ Your Best My Best 生きてるんだから
Yeah! Your Best My Best, because we're alive...
失敗なんてメッじゃない！
...failures are nothing!
笑う門に福来たるでしょ
Good fortune comes to those who smile, right?
ネガティブだって吹っ飛ぶ！
Even negatives will blow away!
命の花咲かせて思い切り
Let the flowers of life bloom with all our might...
もっとバリバリ！
...more and more!
プリキュア！
Pretty Cure!
プリティでキュアキュア
Pretty and Cure Cure...
ふたりは
the two of us...
プリキュア！
...are Pretty Cure!
Pretty Cure!
プリキュア！
マックスパワー！
Max Power!
イェーイ！踊ったね！
Yay! We danced!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
もう、ぼたんちゃんすごかったよー！
Man, Botan-chan, you were amazing!
めっちゃ楽しかった。これはもうアイドルだったよね。
It was so much fun. We were totally idols just now.
完全にアイドル。完全にアイドルでした。
Completely idols. We were completely idols.
なので、今からアイドルのね、撮影会なんかをやっちゃおうかなと。
So, I thought we'd have an idol photo session now.
一緒に撮ろう。スクショ、え、初めてだよね？こうやって載るの。
Let's take photos together. Screenshots, wait, this is the first time, right? Appearing like this.
あ、そう。たぶん3Dで一緒に映るのは初めてだ。
Ah, right. I think it's the first time we're appearing in 3D together.
そうだ、初めてだ！
That's right, the first time!
これはレア映像だ。みんな。
This is rare footage, everyone.
イェイイェイイェイ！
Yay yay yay!
あ、じゃあこの後ろの画像みたいに...
Oh, let's do it like the image behind us...
これね！これ。
This one! This one.
じゃあこんな感じか？
So, like this?
あ、でもこう見えるかな？
Ah, but can you see it like this?
あ、いいじゃん。かぶっていい感じじゃん、これ。
Ah, nice. It looks good overlapping. This.
こう、こう、こんな感じか？
Like this, like this?
撮れたかな？こんな感じ？
Did you get it? Like this?
撮れてる？撮れてる？
Getting it? Getting it?
撮れてるね。撮れてる。
You're getting it. Getting it.
オッケー。撮れた？撮れた？
Okay. Got it? Got it?
撮れたね。
Got it.
みんな撮れた？
Did everyone get it?
撮れたね。
Got it.
え、じゃあ次次！
Wait, next next!
次はちょっと何かやっぱりこう、戦うみたいな感じでさ。
Next, let's do something like fighting.
プリキュアみたいな。
Like Pretty Cure.
こうかな？
Like this?
あ、かっこいいかも。
Ah, that might be cool.
かっこいい？
Cool?
かっこいいかも。
Might be cool.
キリッ。
Sharp.
かっこいい。
Cool.
どうだろう？かっこいいかな。
I wonder. Is it cool?
撮れた？撮れた？
Got it? Got it?
撮れたよね。
You got it, right?
かっこいいの撮れました？
Did you get a cool one?
撮れた。
Got it.
シュッ！シュッ！シュッ！
Whoosh! Whoosh! Whoosh!
なんかあるかな？
Anything else?
あ、なんかさ、ジャンプした瞬間撮ってもらえない？
Ah, can you get one the moment we jump?
いいよ！
Sure!
せーの、シュッ！
Ready, set, whoosh!
撮れたかな？撮れた？
Did you get it? Got it?
たぶんみんなボタン連打してる。
Everyone's probably mashing the button.
あ、ボタンだけにね。
Ah, because of "Botan".
ごめんなさい、ちょっとクソつまらないこと言っちゃった。
Sorry, I said something really lame.
いいよ、あれやりたい。
It's okay, I want to do that.
あのさ、ガオガオポーズ。
The "Gao Gao" pose.
いいよ。
Sure.
ガオガオ。イヌ科同士だからね。
Gao Gao. Since we're both canines.
実はネコ科なんです。
Actually, I'm a feline.
カットでお願いします！マジでカットで！
Edit that out, please! Seriously, cut it!
カットで！
Cut it!
今日だけ、今日だけイヌ科になるんで。
Just for today, I'll be a canine.
アイ、アイ、ガオー。
I, I, Gao.
カットしました？
Did you cut it?
今日だけイヌ科です。
Just for today, I'm a canine.
よかった、今日だけ限定でね。
Glad to hear it, limited to today.
さあ、ほか何かある？
Now, anything else?
ハシゴ！ハシゴ！
Ladder! Ladder!
撮れた？ハシゴ。
Did you get it? Ladder.
あ、いい子いい子。
Ah, good girl, good girl.
いい感じいい感じ。
Looking good, looking good.
どうす、あと、あと、あと...
What else, next, next...
これまだ時間平気だよ。
We still have plenty of time.
1時間も2時間も大丈夫。
An hour or two is fine.
まじ？
Really?
うん、平気だよ。
Yeah, it's fine.
でもね、ちょっとね、そろそろ...
But, well, it's about time...
やだー！
No way!
次の方の...
The next person's...
あ、すみません。
Ah, sorry.
じゃあここにいていい？
Then can I stay here?
あ、次の方の、ちょっとお時間もありますんで。
Ah, we have the next person's time too.
押してますんで。
We're running over.
すみませんね。
Sorry.
じゃあちょっと、ありがとうございました！
Well then, thank you very much!
ころね先輩でした！
It was Korone-senpai!
わー！まだおる！
Whoa! She's still here!
わー！
Whoa!
はい、帰って帰って。
Okay, go home, go home.
わー！
Whoa!
あー、ころね先輩帰っちゃったけど、また今度一緒に歌ってもらおうかな。
Ah, Korone-senpai went home, but I think I'll ask her to sing with me again sometime.
じゃあちょっとね、次は、今日はアイドルということでぴったりの歌をちょっとね、持ってきたんで。
So, next, since today is about being an idol, I've brought a song that's perfect for that.
よかったらみんなも一緒にコールをね、してもらえたら嬉しいかなと思います。
I'd be happy if everyone could join in with the calls too.
じゃあ早速、次の曲行ってみましょう。
Then without further ado, let's go to the next song.
私、アイドル宣言。
"Watashi, Idol Sengen".
可愛くね
Be cute.
とびきりの愛よ届け！
Deliver this special love!
名前だけでも...
Even just my name...
覚えて帰ってください (ハイ！)
Please remember it before you go (Hey!)
レッスン開始！
Lesson start!
意気込むけれど
I'm enthusiastic, but
歌って♪
Singing♪
踊って♪
Dancing♪
ヘトヘト(;´Д`)
Exhausted (;´Д`)
比較される
Compared
事もあるけど
It happens sometimes, but
私は！
I!
私で！
Am me!
ありたい！
And that's who I want to be!
本気出さなきゃ
If I don't give it my all
響かないんだ
It won't resonate
ファンの心を
The hearts of the fans
掴みたいんだ
I want to grab
だから
So
スタート全開
Starting at full speed
飛ばしますよっ
I'm going to take off!
You are my angel
可愛くね
Be cute
とびきりの愛よ届け！！！
Send out your best love!!!
宜しければ名前だけでも...
If you'd like, even just my name...
覚えて帰ってください m(_ _)m
Please remember it before you go m(_ _)m
あざとくね
Be calculate-ly cute
とびきりのスマイルで！！！
With the best smile!!!
宜しければ推しにしちゃって...
If you'd like, make me your favorite...
くれませんか？！っ
Won't you?!
なんてね
Just kidding
ちょっぴりマジなの
I'm a little serious
期待していいですか？
Can I have expectations?
人生変える
Changing life
そんな一日
A day like that
憧れ！
Adored!
夢見た！
Dreamed of!
ステージ
Stage
オシャレ？
Fashionable?
流行り？
Trendy?
追いつけなくて
Can't keep up
言い訳
Excuses
弱音も
complaints
出ちゃうよ(;´Д`)
Might slip out (;´Д`)
向いてないかな？
Am I not suited for this?
愛想悪いし
I'm not very sociable
こんなアイドル
An idol like this
他にいないし
There's no one else like me
でもね
But you know
絶対絶対
Definitely, definitely
見返すんだっ！
I'll prove them wrong!
愛してね
Please love me
日本一夢見てる
Dreaming of being number one in Japan
宜しければ愛の手一つ
If you'd like, give me a hand of love
入れてやってください m(_ _)m
Please join in m(_ _)m
手を挙げて
Raise your hands
視線独り占めして！
Monopolize my gaze!
宜しければ愛を恵んで...
If you'd like, bestow your love...
くれませんか？！っ
Won't you?!
なんてね
Just kidding
絶対後悔
Definitely regret
させませんよマジでねっ！！
I won't let you, I'm serious!!
今もステージは
Even now the stage is
胸がキュッと熱くなる
Making my heart race and heat up
揺れる景色焼き付けて
Etching the swaying scenery into my mind
歌う声に愛を込めるっ
Putting love into my singing voice
響く歓声
The echoing cheers
気持ち高鳴る
My heart is racing
これは証明
This is proof
私ここだよ
I am right here
いくよ？絶対絶対
Here I go? Definitely, definitely
声出してね
Let your voice out
可愛くね
Be cute
とびきりの愛よ届け！！！
Send out your best love!!!
宜しければ名前だけでも...
If you'd like, even just my name...
覚えて帰ってください m(_ _)m
Please remember it before you go m(_ _)m
あざとくね
Be calculate-ly cute
とびきりのスマイルで！！！
With the best smile!!!
宜しければ推しにしちゃって...
If you'd like, make me your favorite...
くれませんか？！っ
Won't you?!
なんてね
Just kidding
ちょっぴりマジなの
I'm a little serious
期待していいですか？
Can I have expectations?
はい！ということで、
Yes! And with that,
3曲歌ってきました。
I've sung three songs.
まあやっぱり今日はね、アイドルがテーマなので
Well, after all, today's theme is "idol,"
アイドル宣言は外せないかなと思ってたんですよね。
so I thought "Idol Sengen" was a must-have.
じゃあちょっとね、次、あれ？
Now then, next, oh?
あれ？なんか、
Oh? Something...
すっごい美味しそうな匂いがする。
smells really delicious.
おら！
Hey!
おら！ジンギスカン！
Hey! Genghis Khan!
ということで、次の、あ、食材じゃねえ、
So, the next, ah, not ingredient...
次のゲストの、
...next guest,
角巻わため先輩です！
...is Tsunomaki Watame-senpai!
食材じゃねーぞ！わためだぞ！
I'm not an ingredient! I'm Watame!
ちょっと隅からごめんなさいね。
Sorry to interrupt from the corner.
美味しそうな匂いがちょっとちらちらちらちら。
A delicious smell kept wafting over.
いつ呼ばれるか待ってたんだけど。
I was waiting to be called.
本当？ごめんなさいね。ありがとうございます、今日は。
Really? I'm sorry. Thank you for today.
獅白の1周年に。
For Shishiro's 1st anniversary.
こちらこそ！1周年おめでとう！
Likewise! Happy 1st anniversary!
一周年！おめでとうございます！
First anniversary! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いや、なんかな。もう一年なのかって気分なんですけど。
Well, somehow. I feel like, "Is it already a year?"
ねー。早いですよね。
Yeah. Time flies, doesn't it?
ね。今日はね、もうアイドルがテーマなんで。
Right. Today's theme is idols.
わため先輩にもちょっとアイドルになってもらおうかな。
I'm going to have Watame-senpai become an idol too.
やっちゃおうかな。きゃっぴ！
Shall I do it? Kyappi!
あ、かわいい。これは食べ甲斐がありますね。
Ah, cute. This makes me want to eat you.
やめなーい！食べるんじゃないー！
Stop it! Don't eat me!
今日はね、ちょっとわためと一緒に歌いたい歌がありまして。
Today, there's a song I want to sing with Watame.
私たちいつも、あの肉食系と草食系じゃないですか。
We're always carnivore and herbivore, right?
そうですね。
That's right.
ちょっとね、理系っぽい歌。
A bit of a science-ish song.
おっ、理系？
Oh, science?
理系、っぽい歌。
Science-ish song.
理系じゃなくても大丈夫？
Is it okay if I'm not a science major?
大丈夫です。文系でも大丈夫です。
It's fine. Humanities majors are okay too.
文系でもないけど大丈夫？
I'm not humanities either, but is it okay?
何系でも大丈夫です。
Any major is fine.
はい。じゃあ、そういうことで。歌っていきたいかなと。
Right. So, let's get to singing.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ、いいですか？タイトルコール一緒に、お願いします。
Ready? Please do the title call with me.
はい。
Okay.
せーの、チューリングラブ！
One, two, Turing Love!
チューリングラブ
作詞：ナユタセイジ／ナユタアカリ　作曲：ナユタセイジ
Turing Love
Lyrics: Nayuta Seiji / Nayuta Akari  Music: Nayuta Seiji
あー、恋の定義が分かんない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まず好きって基準もわかんない
First, I don't even know the criteria for "liking"
要は恋してる時が恋だし
In short, love is when you're in love
客観、エビデンス、プリーズ！
Objective evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved with calculations
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve ordinary calculations
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that state is lovely
I know, You know, もう大抵の
I know, You know, most of the
事象においてQがあってAを出して解けるのに
Events can be solved with a Q and an A, but
勘違って間違って解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
What is this unsolvable feeling?
検証 with me　感情motionは相対性理論に
Verification with me, emotions into relativity
チューリングラブ　見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, an unsolvable mellow
What is love?　いま123で明かそうか
What is love? Shall we reveal it now with 123?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン　ハートで高鳴るアンサー
A question created by words, an answer from the heart
測ったって不確定性　ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty even if measured, our BPM
チューリングラブ　証明に待ったって信じないけど
Turing Love, I won't believe even if I wait for proof
フォーリンラブ　いまはABCすら分かりそうだ
Fall in love, now I feel like I understand even ABC
論理で教えてオイラー　感想聞かせてフェルマー
Tell me the logic, Euler. Tell me your thoughts, Fermat
予測不可能性に　いま触れてみる
I'll try touching the unpredictability now
さあ証明しよう　間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it, without any mistakes
さあ証明しよう　この感情全部全部
Come on, let's prove it, all of these emotions
さあ証明しよう　正解があるなら
Come on, let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう　シンプルなQ.E.D.
Come on, let's prove it, a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したいよ　目に見えない無理なんだよ ASAP
I want to prove it today. It's invisible. ASAP
導き出したい　辿り着きたい　最適解へ
I want to reach the optimal solution
何回絡まったってぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times we get tangled
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ実用条件です
Unraveling this anomaly is a practical condition
三次元（カッコ立体）における2点A,B間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between points A and B in 3D
いい感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was going well
座標も公式も見当たらないし
I can't find coordinates or formulas
参考資料にも載っていないから
It's not in the reference materials either
君と編み出して見せたいじゃん
I want to create it with you
三次元（カッコ世界）におけるこの気持ちの求めかた
How to find this feeling in this world
バグだって　バツだって　上書き取っていこうぜ
Let's go and overwrite even bugs or mistakes
近くなって　遠くなって　揺れるこの気持ちの針も
This oscillating needle of my heart too
直系で明快な　デティミネーション
A direct and clear determination
相対性理論に
Into the theory of relativity
チューリングラブ　騒ぎだした胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love, making my heart ache
証明は　いまも角度増しているようだ
The proof seems to be gaining momentum now
曖昧を排除して　最大の仮説を
Eliminating ambiguity, the greatest hypothesis
いま二人なら実証できそう
Now the two of us can demonstrate it
チューリングラブ　見つめあったって切りきれないメロウ
Turing Love, a mellow that can't be cut
What is love?　いま1to3で明かそうか
What is love? Shall we reveal it now with 1 to 3?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン　ハートで高鳴るアンサー
A question created by words, an answer from the heart
測ったって不確定性　ぼくらのBPM
Uncertainty even if measured, our BPM
チューリングラブ　証明に待ったってそう因果も
Turing Love, wait for the proof, even the causality
フォーリンラブ　いまはXYZまで分かりそうだ
Fall in love, now I feel like I understand even XYZ
確かめさせてピタゴラス　足し算させてリーマン
Let me confirm, Pythagoras. Let me add up, Riemann
予測済み仮定に　いま触れてみる
I'll try touching the predicted assumption now
さあ証明しよう　間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it, without any mistakes
さあ証明しよう　この感情全部全部
Come on, let's prove it, all of these emotions
さあ証明しよう　正解があるなら
Come on, let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう　最小値超えて
Come on, let's prove it, exceeding the minimum value
さあ証明しよう　間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it, without any mistakes
さあ証明しよう　この感情全部全部
Come on, let's prove it, all of these emotions
さあ証明しよう　正解があるなら
Come on, let's prove it, if there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう　シンプルなQ.E.D.
Come on, let's prove it, a simple Q.E.D.
わあ！イエーイ！
Waa! Yay!
最後さ... あの、手振ったんだけどさ、気づいた？
At the end... Um, I waved my hand, did you notice?
気づいた！あとから振ったんだけどさ、気づいた？
I noticed! I waved back afterwards, did you notice?
うん、気づいた。
Yeah, I noticed.
すれ違ってたよな。
We missed each other, didn't we?
すれ違っちゃった。
We missed each other.
あるあるだね。
It happens.
そうだね。
It does.
でね、ちょっとね、まだ時間あるからさ...
And, well, we still have a bit of time...
スクショタイムなんかどうでしょう。
How about some screenshot time?
いいね！
Sounds good!
なんか、ポーズある？やりたいポーズある？
Any poses you want to do?
なんかある？
Is there anything?
いつもさ、いつもなんかこう、こういう感じじゃん、いつも。
Usually, it's always like this, you know, always.
逆は？
What about the opposite?
ガオー！
Gao! (Roar)
もっと怖がってよ！
Be more scared!
ガオー！もっと...うー、うー...
Gao! More... uuu, uuu...
もっと怖がれ！
Be scarier!
笑顔なんだな。
You're smiling, though.
怖がってる？ちゃんと。
Are you properly scared?
怖がってるよ。こわいこわい。
I'm scared. Scary, scary.
お手本見せてあげる。
I'll show you an example.
ほんと？
Really?
うー... ひい！
Uuu... Hii!
お、めっちゃ怖がってる。
Whoa, she's really scared.
こわいよー。助けてー。
It's scary! Help!
すごい。
Amazing.
これか！
So this is it!
じゃあ、もう一回やっていい？
Okay, can we do it again?
いいよ。
Sure.
行くよ。
Here I go.
はい。
Okay.
ガオー！ うわー！こわいよー！
Gao! Uwaa! Scary!
なんか怖くなくなってきたな。
It's starting to not feel scary anymore.
なんか、ね。
Yeah, kinda.
なんか余裕がある。
There's some leeway.
ちょっと余裕あったね。
I had a bit of leeway.
なんでー！なんでよ！
Why?! Why?!
え、他でも、まあやっぱり一周年記念、なんかちょっと可愛いポーズしたいな。
Well, for the 1st anniversary, I want to do a cute pose too.
したいね！
I want to!
え、なんか...
Um, like...
チューリングラブの時のさ...
Like from 'Turing Love'...
チュー...リン...ラブ、ラブ、ラブ。
Tu-ring-love, love, love.
え、いいの？
Is this okay?
いいよ。ハートにしない？
It's fine. Shall we make a heart?
うー... うー...
Uuu... Uuu...
あ、ハートになっちゃった。
Ah, it became a heart.
見えるかな？
Can they see it?
むずいな。
It's hard.
なんとか、なんとか...
Somehow, somehow...
みんながハートに見えるように見てください。
Everyone, please look at it so it looks like a heart!
あ、できたんじゃない？
Oh, didn't we do it?
できたんじゃない？
Didn't we?
どう？誰がどう見てもハートだ。
How is it? It's a heart no matter how you look at it.
これがハートなんだ。
So this is a heart.
これがハートだ。
This is a heart.
我々のハートだ。
Our heart.
背中合わせとか。
How about back-to-back?
かっこいい。かっこいい。
Cool! Cool!
たまにはかっこいいわためもちょっと見たいね。
I want to see a cool Watame once in a while too.
かっこいい？
Cool?
どう？あ、いいんね、かっこいいね、わため。
How's that? Oh, nice, you look cool, Watame.
いいね！
Nice!
いいね！かっこいい！
Nice! Cool!
お、いい、いい。
Oh, good, good.
アー写だね。みんな撮ってる？大丈夫？
It's like a profile pic. Is everyone getting it? Okay?
ギュー！
Gyuu!
かっこいいなあ。
So cool.
いいね。いいね。
Nice. Nice.
あ、じゃあね、わためさん、ちょっとね、申し訳ない。
Ah, well, Watame-san, I'm sorry.
え？なに？
Eh? What?
お時間の方が迫ってきているらしいんですよ。
It seems time is running out.
わかんない！
I don't know!
お時間？なに？わかんない！
Time? What? I don't know!
あ、ちょっと閉店のお時間。
Ah, it's almost closing time.
閉店？！
Closing?!
嫌だー！絶対ここにいる！
No! I'm definitely staying here!
ずっといるー！
I'll stay forever!
居座る！
I'm staying put!
やめてー！やめちくりー！やめないでー！
Stop! Please stop! Don't do that!
やめないでー！食べないでー！
Don't stop! Don't eat me!
くそ、逃げられた。
Damn, she escaped.
ちょっとわためはまた今度追いかけるとして。
I'll chase Watame another time.
じゃあ、次の曲なんですけれども...
Now, for the next song...
えっとね、これね、私がボカロの歌を歌うことって...
Um, you know, me singing Vocaloid songs...
ま、今日一曲目、あのハッピーシンセサイザ歌ったと思うんですけど、あんまりなくて、普段。
Well, I sang 'Happy Synthesizer' as the first song today, but usually I don't do it much.
でも今日はちょっと、好きなボカロの曲がね、あったので...
But today, there was a Vocaloid song I like...
歌わせてもらおうかなと、思います。
So I thought I'd give it a sing.
それでは、聞いてください。帝国少女。
Now, please listen. 'Teikoku Shoujo'.
帝国少女
作詞・作曲：R Sound Design
Teikoku Shoujo (Imperial Girl)
Lyrics & Composition: R Sound Design
はいはい 排他的都市構想
浮ついた世のシーンでのメロディに
Yes, yes, exclusive urban vision.
To the melody in the scenes of this restless world.
雑踏の中 息衝いた Trap
Neon アラカルト
A trap that breathed in the bustle.
Neon à la carte.
感傷的都市少女
Sentimental urban girl.
フラついた夜のミームとメロディ
彷徨って行き着いた路地裏の闇夜に溶ける
Night memes and melodies that faltered.
Wandering and arriving, melting into the dark night of the back alleys.
感傷的都市構想
騒めいた夜のホールでパッと言って
Sentimental urban vision.
Briefly spoken in the bustling night hall.
喧騒の中、色褪せたVaporwave
In the hustle and bustle, faded vaporwave
紛れ込み、トポロジー絶対的都市抗争
Mingling in, topology of absolute urban conflict
イラついた今日のあいつをバタニー
Today's irritating guy, batter up
強がって噛み付いた、聳える都市のシステム
Acting tough and biting back at the towering city system
鈍金製の結合環を、左の耳にぶら下げて
Hanging a dull-golden coupling ring from my left ear
芳香性の憂鬱感を纏ったら
Once draped in a fragrant melancholy
抗菌性の停滞感を、両手の爪に散りばめて
Embedding antimicrobial stagnation in my fingernails
どうせ何も起こることのない、この夜に
In this night where nothing will happen anyway
朽ち行く体と心連れ、独り宛もなく、くたばっていくの
Taking my decaying body and soul, I'm dying alone with no destination
形骸的記号に曝され、彷徨う都市を這い回るゾンビ
Exposed to skeletal symbols, a zombie crawling around the wandering city
どんなに、どんなに夜に落ちても、明日の光が世界を染めていく
No matter how deep I fall into the night, tomorrow's light will stain the world
蘇る私は、帝国少女
Reborn, I am Imperial Girl
盲目的都市幻想
Blind urban fantasy
犇めき合うステップ、ドップラーと漂うクロエ
Crowding steps, Chloe drifting with the Doppler effect
私をちょっと狂わせる、プッシャー、Wave Pablo
The pusher who drives me a little crazy, Wave Pablo
トポロジー恋愛都市様相
Topology of romantic urban aspects
目眩く夜とジーンのシャワーに
In the dizzying night and a shower of genes
浸り濡れた指の先で、なぞる恋のケミカル
Tracing the chemicals of love with my soaked fingertips
混成の背徳感を、薬指に光らせて
Shining a hybrid sense of immorality on my ring finger
浸食性の優越感にそれを、通して
Passing it through a corrosive sense of superiority
後天性の先入観で、両目の縁を彩った
With acquired prejudice, I colored the edges of both eyes
違う人共の部屋で夢見るなら、もう
If I'm to dream in other people's rooms, then already...
私の体と心、傷つけた罪を償いなさい
Atone for the sin of wounding my body and soul
衝動的感情に流されて、行き着く先は暗い泥より
Washed away by impulsive emotions, reaching a place darker than mud
あんまりな、あんまりな仕打ちだわ、貴方に愛して欲しかっただけ
What a cruel, cruel thing to do; I only wanted you to love me
蘇る私は、帝国少女
Reborn, I am Imperial Girl
もうやるせない昨日の日々も、揺れる摩天楼に抱かれて
Even the helpless days of yesterday, embraced by the swaying skyscrapers
ビルに塗れる夜空の星に、願いを込める、こんな夜に
Into the stars in the night sky smeared by buildings, I pour my wishes on a night like this
朽ち行く体と心連れ、独り宛もなく、くたばっていくの
Taking my decaying body and soul, I'm dying alone with no destination
形骸的記号に曝され、彷徨う都市を這い回るゾンビ
Exposed to skeletal symbols, a zombie crawling around the wandering city
どんなに、どんなに夜に落ちても、明日の光が世界を染めていく
No matter how deep I fall into the night, tomorrow's light will stain the world
未来などどうでもいいのよ
I don't care about the future at all
こんなに、こんなに愛した場所、何度も何度も這い回った道
This place I loved so, so much; the path I crawled over again and again
最期まで凶手に追われた、黄昏の街、駆け抜けるゾンビ
A zombie running through the twilight city, chased by a killer until the end
私の体と心の傷、貴方の笑顔も声も全部
The wounds on my body and soul, your smile, your voice, everything
ここに置いていくわ、帝国少女
I'll leave it all here, Imperial Girl
はい、ということで皆さん、ありがとうございましたー！
Alright, so everyone, thank you very much!
お、もう半分は終わったのかな？用意してた曲。
Oh, is that half of the songs I prepared already finished?
じゃあちょっと、そろそろあれかな？次のゲストの方、待ち合わせしてたんだけどなー。
Well then, I guess it's about time? I was supposed to meet the next guest...
あれ？
Huh?
なんか、なんかおる。
Someone's... someone's here.
あー！
Aah!
うわー、尻尾引っ張られてびっくりしたー。
Whoa, you pulling my tail gave me a fright.
あったー。いいお尻してるねー。
Found you. You've got a nice butt.
いぼたんとも、お、いいお尻してるねー。
Botan, too... oh, you've got a nice butt.
ということで、次の、三人目のゲスト！猫又おかゆ先輩です！
So, our next, third guest is Nekomata Okayu-senpai!
わー、呼んでくれてありがとう。
Yay, thanks for inviting me.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
おかゆでーよ。
It's Okayu~.
ということで、一周年記念、ありがとうございます、来ていただいて。
Anyway, thank you for coming to my first anniversary.
いやいや、こちらこそ。おめでとう一周年！
No, no, same here. Congrats on your first anniversary!
ありがとうございます。早いもので、もうちょっとね、一周年。
Thank you. Time flies; it's already been a year.
あっという間だったね。
It went by in a flash, didn't it?
あっという間でした。
It really was in a flash.
なんか、あれだね。おかゆ先輩と並ぶとさ。
You know... standing next to Okayu-senpai...
うん。
Yeah.
なんかちょっと、あれっぽくない？なんか、
Doesn't it look a bit like... you know?
なんかもう、ちょっと僕ちんちくりんすぎてやばい。
It's just that I'm way too short, it's crazy.
あれ？
Huh?
僕の方が、全然先輩なんだぞ。
I'm totally your senior, you know.
すみませんね、背が高くて。
Sorry for being so tall.
なんでこんな大きいんだよ。
Why are you so big?!
なんかこれじゃ僕が、ぼたんちゃんのさ、なんか射程の何？底の部分みたいになって。
Like this, I'm like... what, the bottom part of Botan-chan's range?
底の部分。
Bottom part.
弟の部分。
Like a little brother.
弟みたい。
おい！うちのぼたん姉さんに何か用かよ！
Hey! You got business with our Botan-nee?!
おお、あんのか、コノヤロー！
Oh, you want some, you jerk?!
おらー！
Oraaa!
あー！
Aaah!
うわ、ぼたん、ぼたん姉さんにさあ、
Whoa, Botan... Botan-neesan...
うわ！あ、かかってこいや！
Whoa! Hey, bring it on!
かかってこいやー！
Bring it on!
ぼたん姉さんに話があんなら、
If you've got business with Botan-neesan,
まず僕に声をかけてくんないと困るんだけど。
you'd better talk to me first.
お、お、おかゆ先輩になあ、手出してえんなら、
If you try to lay a hand on Okayu-senpai,
ただじゃおかねえぞ！
I won't let you off easy!
ぼたん姉さん、仲良しかあ？
Botan-neesan, we're good friends, aren't we?
うわあ、かかってこいや！
Whoa, bring it on!
今日はな、二人でな、アイドルするんだよ！
Today, the two of us are gonna be idols!
アイドル？な、な、なんか歌うのかい？
Idols? Are we gonna sing something?
歌うぞ。今日はな、おかゆ先輩とな、
We are. Today, with Okayu-senpai...
アイドルと言いつつちょっとかっこいい曲を歌うんだ。
...we'll sing a cool song while being idols.
何歌うんだ？教えてくれよ。
What are we singing? Tell me.
じゃ、一緒にタイトルコール、お願いしてもいいかな？
Can I ask you to do the title call with me?
いいよ。
Sure.
行くぞ。
Let's go.
じゃあ、行くぞ！
Alright, let's go!
せーの！
One, two!
LOSER!
LOSER
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
いつもどおりの通り独り
Alone on the same street as always
こんな日々もはや懲り懲り
I'm already sick of these days
もうどこにも行きやしないのに
Though I'm not going anywhere
夢見ておやすみ
Goodnight, dreaming a dream
いつでも僕らはこんなふうに
We're always like this
ぼんくらな夜に飽き飽き
Sick and tired of these dimwitted nights
まだ踊り踊り出す明日に
Still dancing, moving toward a tomorrow
出会うためにさよなら
Goodbye, so that we can meet it
歩き回ってやっと着いた
Walked all over and finally arrived
ここはどうだ楽園か
What's it like here? Is it paradise?
今となっちゃもうわからない
Now I don't even know anymore
四半世紀の結果出来た
The result of a quarter century
青い顔のスパースターが
A pale-faced superstar
お腹すかして待ってる
Is waiting with an empty stomach
I'm a LOSER
どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう
Might as well be a distant howl
もう一回もう一回行こうぜ
Let's go one more time, one more time
僕らの声
Our voices
I'm a LOSER
ずっと前から聞こえてた
I've heard it since a long time ago
いつかポケットに隠した声が
The voice I once hid in my pocket
ああだこうだの知ったもんか
Who cares about this or that?
幸先の空は悪天候
The promising sky is bad weather
ほら窓から覗いた摩天楼
Look at the skyscrapers through the window
カラスりゃチリのよう
From here, they look like dust
阿んも可とも昔の人よ
Both 'A' and 'Un' are people of the past
中指立ててもしょうがないの
Giving the finger doesn't help
今勝ち上がるためのお勉強
I'm studying to win right now
朗らかな表情
With a cheerful expression
踊る阿呆に見る阿呆
A fool dancing and a fool watching
我らそれを端から笑う阿呆
We're the fools laughing at them from the side
デカい自意識抱え込んでは摩耗
Clutching a huge ego until it's worn out
擦り減って残るサバイブドッグ
A surviving dog remaining after attrition
膝抱えても何もねえ
Holding my knees gets me nowhere
ほら長い前髪で前が見えねえ
Look, I can't see forward through my long bangs
笑っちまうねパッと沸き立って
It's laughable, boiling up suddenly
フワッと消えちゃえるこんな輪廻
And softly disappearing, this kind of cycle
愛されたいならそう言おうぜ
If you want to be loved, just say so
思ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね
Just thinking it won't get it across
永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて
Even the eternal lady turns away
天国は遠く向こうのほうへ
Heaven is far off in the distance
ああ、わかってるって深く転がる
Ah, I know, rolling deep down
俺は負け犬
I'm a loser
ただどこでもいいから遠くへ行きたいんだ
I just want to go far away, anywhere's fine
それだけなんだ
That's all it is
耳を澄ませ遠くで今
Listen closely, far off now
響き出した音を逃すな
Don't miss the sound that's started to ring
呼吸を整えて
Steady your breath
いつかは出会えるはずの
One day I'm sure to meet it
黄金の色したアイライト
The golden-colored eye light
きっと掴んで離すな
I'll surely grab it and never let go
I'm a LOSER
何もないならどうなったっていいだろう
If there's nothing, then anything goes, right?
うだうだしてフラフラしていちゃ今に
Loitering and wandering about, and soon
ハイさよなら
Bang, goodbye
I'm a LOSER
きっといつかって願うまま進め
Proceed as you wish for 'someday'
ロスタイムのそのまた奥へ行け
Go even deeper into the lost time
愛されたいならそう言おうぜ
If you want to be loved, just say so
思ってるだけじゃ伝わらないね
Just thinking it won't get it across
永遠の淑女もそっぽ向いて
Even the eternal lady turns away
天国は遠く向こうのほうへ
Heaven is far off in the distance
ここいらで一丁踊ってみようぜ
Let's give it a go and dance right here
夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until the dawn
聞こえてんなら声出していこうぜ
If you can hear it, let's let our voices out
I'm a LOSER
どうせだったら遠吠えだっていいだろう
Might as well be a distant howl
もう一回もう一回行こうぜ
Let's go one more time, one more time
僕らの声
Our voices
I'm a LOSER
ずっと前から聞こえてた
I've heard it since a long time ago
いつかポケットに隠した声が
The voice I once hid in my pocket
ここいらで一丁踊ってみようぜ
Let's give it a go and dance right here
夜が明けるまで転がっていこうぜ
Let's keep rolling until the dawn
聞こえてんなら声出していこうぜ
If you can hear it, let's let our voices out
えい！
Ey!
えー、私たちのLOSERどうだったー！？
So, how was our performance of LOSER!?
どうだったおらー！
How was it, huh!?
俺たちのアイドル見たか？
Did you see us as idols?
アイドルだったろ、おらー！
We were idols, right!?
おらおら、カメラこっち寄って来い！
Hey hey, camera, come closer!
ストー、ストー、スクショ、スクショ！
S- s- screenshot time! Screenshot time!
やめ、大丈夫かな？
Wait, is this okay?
そんなとこ押さえないの！
Don't hold me there!
こうやってね、一緒に並んだりするの初めてだからさ。
It's actually our first time standing together like this.
おら！おい寄って来い！
Hey! Come closer!
もっと！ガチ恋上等だおら！
More! Falling for us is totally fine, hey!
ガチ恋上等だぞおら！
Falling for us is totally fine!
ガチ恋上等だおら！
こんな近づくことなくて...
We never get this close...
こんな...アイドルの裏側全部おら！
This is... all the behind-the-scenes of idols!
カメラこっち押さえないぞ！アイドル全部おら！
Don't hold the camera there! Everything about idols!
あ、ぼたんちゃん僕...もうそろそろ行かなきゃいけない時間みたいだ。
Ah, Botan-chan, I... it looks like it's almost time for me to go.
やだ！
No way!
ぼたんちゃんが...そういうキャラだっけ？ぼたんちゃん。
Botan-chan... was she always this kind of character?
もっといてよ、おかゆ先輩...寂しくなっちゃったの？
Stay longer, Okayu-senpai... Did you get lonely?
そう、可愛いね、よしよしよしよしよし。
Yeah, so cute. There, there.
でも帰る！
But I'm leaving!
あ！おかゆ先輩！
Ah! Okayu-senpai!
じゃあね！
See ya!
あー、待ってー！
Ah, wait!
あ〜、おかゆ先輩行ってしまった...
Ah, Okayu-senpai has left...
いや、でも今日は本当に3名のゲストの方にお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Well, but thank you very much to the three guests for coming today.
ということで、ここからは獅白ぼたんのソロになりますけれども...
So, from here on, it'll be Shishiro Botan's solo performance...
次の曲はですね、ま、ちょっとしっとりした感じの...
The next song is, well, a bit of a sentimental one...
でもなんか私が好きな曲を今日集めているので、ちょっとね、ぜひ聴いていただければと思います。
I've gathered songs that I like today, so I'd love for you to listen to it.
それではいってみましょう。ルーマー。
Well then, let's get started. Rumor.
ルーマー
作詞・作曲：ポリスピカデリー
Rumor
Lyrics/Composition: Police Piccadilly
だいぶ参っちゃったね 笑えもしない
I'm quite beat, I can't even laugh
今宵 まやかしさ 引き取って頂戴
Tonight, it's a deception, please take it away
損問題なのは 魔法みたいにさ
The problem is, like magic
理想 吸われるのが 早過ぎ
My ideals are being sucked away too fast
霞がまだ掛かってるの
Mist is still hanging over
それこそメンタルやられるよ
That itself will destroy my mental state
ぶら下がって切り抜けるなんてと
Hanging on to get through it...
嫌いになれない 辞めたいよ 本当
I can't hate it, I want to quit, really
どうにも手の負えない 愛々愛 見止めてよ
Uncontrollable love-love-love, notice it
輝かなくなるよ
It's going to stop shining
目論見通りの 振る舞いも 掬い切れないよ 舞
Even the planned behavior can't be fully scooped up, dance
最高潮のタッチ 跳ね上がる ハートビート
High peak touch, leaping heartbeat
覚えてしまう程 戻れない位
To the point I remember it, to the point I can't go back
踏み入れて回るの 捧げライフ
Stepping in and spinning, dedicated life
初めから解って
Knowing from the start
薄っぺらだね 余多嫌な感じ
It's thin, isn't it? A lot of unpleasant feelings
気付いてないところが 救い
The fact you haven't noticed is the salvation
誤魔化せない 魔法みたいにさ
Can't deceive it, like magic
今宵のラバー 手回し過ぎ
Tonight's lover, over-preparing
強がりを透かしてるよ
Seeing through the bluff
聴きたいのはこっちの方
I'm the one who wants to hear it
無双砕ける音と空ろ
The sound of matchless crumbling and emptiness
夢でもないのに 辞めたいよ 本当
Even though it's not a dream, I want to quit, really
どうにも手の負えない 愛々愛 見止めてよ
Uncontrollable love-love-love, notice it
輝かなくなるよ
It's going to stop shining
目論見通りの 振る舞いも 掬い切れないよ 舞
Even the planned behavior can't be fully scooped up, dance
最高潮のタッチ 跳ね上がる ハートビート
High peak touch, leaping heartbeat
覚えてしまう程 戻れない位
To the point I remember it, to the point I can't go back
踏み入れて回るの 捧げライフ
Stepping in and spinning, dedicated life
初めから解って
Knowing from the start
隙間を埋める程 導かれるの I'm ready
Being guided enough to fill the gaps, I'm ready
ほらのおまじないも
Even the magic spell
悪くないだろ なんて
Isn't bad, or something
丸ごと何処か余所へやって 新しい期待で満たす
Send it all away somewhere else, fill it with new expectations
いつだって必然だったから
Because it was always inevitable
どうにも手の負えない 愛々愛 見止めてよ
Uncontrollable love-love-love, notice it
輝かなくなるよ
It's going to stop shining
目論見通りの 振る舞いも 掬い切れないよ 舞
Even the planned behavior can't be fully scooped up, dance
最高潮のタッチ 跳ね上がる ハートビート
High peak touch, leaping heartbeat
覚えてしまう程 戻れない位
To the point I remember it, to the point I can't go back
揺らめいても
Even if it flickers,
あの笹原に
in that bamboo thicket,
はじめからわかって
knowing it from the start...
ということで、『ルーマー』でした！
And that was "Rumor"!
それでは、えー続いての曲を連続でいきましょう。
Now, let's move on to the next song right away.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
『海の幽霊』
"Spirits of the Sea"
明け放たれたこの部屋には誰もいない
In this wide-open room, there is no one
潮風の匂い染み付いた椅子が一つ
A single chair, stained with the scent of sea breeze
あなたが迷わないように開けておくよ
I'll keep it open so you don't get lost
海の幽霊
作詞・作曲: 米津玄師
Spirits of the Sea
Lyrics & Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
軋む戸を叩いて
Knock on the creaking door
何から話せばいいのかわからなくなる
I lose track of what to talk about first
かな...
Perhaps...
星が降る夜に
On a night when stars fall
あなたに会えた
I was able to meet you
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night
大切なことは言葉にならない
The important things cannot be put into words
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on that summer day
思いがけず光るのは海の幽霊
What shines unexpectedly are the spirits of the sea
茹だる夏の夕に梢が
On a sweltering summer evening, the treetops...
船を見送る
...watching the ship go
いくつかの歌を囁く
Whispering a few songs
花を散らして
Scattering flowers
あなたがどこかで笑う声が聞こえる
I can hear your voice laughing somewhere
熱い頬の手触り
The feel of warm cheeks
捻れた道を進んだらその瞼が
If I walk down the twisted path, those eyelids...
開く
...will open
離れ離れでも
Even if we are apart
ときめくもの
the things that thrill me...
叫ぼう 今は幸せと
Let's shout out now that we are happy
大切なことは言葉にならない
The important things cannot be put into words
跳ねる光に溶かして
Melting into the bouncing light
星が降る夜に
On a night when stars fall
あなたに会えた
I was able to meet you
あの時を忘れはしない
I will never forget that time
大切なことは言葉にならない
The important things cannot be put into words
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on that summer day
思いがけず光るのは海の幽霊
What shines unexpectedly are the spirits of the sea
風薫る砂浜で
On the breeze-scented beach
また会いましょう
Let's meet again
はい、皆さんありがとうございました！
Yes, thank you everyone!
ということで、『海の幽霊』歌わせていただきました。
And with that, I sang "Spirits of the Sea".
じゃあ、そろそろね、もうね、時間も過ぎてきてるんですけど、
Well, it's about that time, and we're getting towards the end, but...
ここで、告知タイムだー！
Now, it's time for an announcement!
活動一周年記念
8月14日販売開始
1st Anniversary Celebration
Sales start August 14
イエーイ！ドドドドド！
Yay! Dun dun dun dun dun!
パフパフパフパフ！
Pa-fu pa-fu pa-fu pa-fu!
というわけで、活動一周年記念のグッズが出ますので、
So, since my 1st anniversary goods are coming out,
一つずつちょっと、簡単ですが紹介していこうかなと思います。
I'd like to briefly introduce them one by one.
じゃあ、まず一つ目なんですけれども、
Well, first of all,
こちら！ドドン！
here it is! Ta-da!
プレミアムアクリルパネルです！
The Premium Acrylic Panel!
出ますかね？はい。こちら、あの普段出してるアクリルパネルより、
Is it up? Yes. This one is more luxurious than
ちょっと豪華なものになります。
the acrylic panels we usually release.
ちょっと「獅白ぼたん」の文字が、ちょっと浮き出ているというか、
The "Shishiro Botan" text is kind of embossed,
パーツの一部として浮き出てる、
it's raised as part of the piece.
今回は本当にトマリ先生にイラストを描いていただけたので、
Tomari-sensei drew the illustration for us this time,
是非飾ってください！
so please display it!
そして二つ目、こちら！ドン！
And the second one, here! Bam!
ライブタオル！今日はね、あの、「今日はアイドル」っていうテーマで
A live towel! Today's theme is "Today I'm an Idol,"
やってるから、なんかライブっぽいグッズ欲しかったんですよ。
so I really wanted some "live-like" merchandise.
なので、ちょっとライブタオルなるものを作ってみました。
So, I decided to make a live towel.
これ私のね、この袖、袖わかる？
This is... do you see my sleeve?
袖の、この、部分と似たタオルです！
This towel looks just like this part of my sleeve!
これ結構長くて、胸あたりぐらいまであるんで、
It's quite long, reaching about chest level,
もうスポーツに使ってもよし、ライブ行くにもよし、外行くにもよし、
so it's great for sports, concerts, outings,
家で使うもよし。万能タオルとなってますので、是非使ってみてください。
or even just at home. It's a versatile towel, so please use it.
そして次これ！ドン！
And next is this! Bam!
ライブと言えばやっぱり、私キーホルダーのイメージがあって、
Speaking of concerts, I always associate them with keychains,
なので、ライブキーホルダーも作ってみました。
so I made a live keychain as well.
こちら、皆さんに、良かったら、これも！
I hope you guys like this one too!
わかるかな？
Can you tell?
ここの、この袖の部分の、感じを表現しました。
It captures the feel of this part of my sleeve.
是非いろんなところに飾って欲しいです、これ。はい。
I'd love for you to hang it in all sorts of places.
であとは、記念フルボイスと、
Then there's the commemorative full voice and,
えっと、フルセット購入特典の方に、あの、
for those who purchase the full set,
サイン付き、複製なんですが、複製付きサインのポストカードが
a postcard with a signature—it's a reproduction,
付いてくるんですが、今回なんと、サインがオリジナル！
but the signature this time is an original design!
この、一周年記念のライブに合わせて、オリジナルのサインになってます。
It's a special signature made for this 1st anniversary live.
普段の獅白ぼたんのサインじゃないんですよ。
It's different from my usual signature.
なのでちょっとレア感があるサインとなってます。
So it has a bit of a rare feel to it.
アイドルっぽいサインにしてます。
I made it look more "idol-like."
とことん今日はもうアイドルにこだわったんで、よろしくお願いします。
I've really focused on the idol theme today.
こちらはフルセット購入特典となりますので、
This is a bonus for purchasing the full set,
是非あの全部買った方は、大事に飾ってください。はい。
so if you bought it, please treasure it. Yes.
そしてね、ちょっとね、紹介したいことが何点かあるんで紹介します。
And there are a few more things I'd like to announce.
えっと、21時15分から私のファーストオリジナル曲、
At 21:15, my first original song,
「Lioness Pride」という曲なんですが、
"Lioness Pride,"
こちらプレミア公開されます！ドドドドド！
will have its premiere! Dun dun dun dun dun!
こちらは、あの今日21時15分からプレミア公開のあと、
Following the premiere at 21:15 today,
24時、0時ですね。
at 24:00—midnight—
あのストリーミング・ダウンロードサイトで購入可能になるので、
it'll be available on streaming and download sites,
もしよかったら是非、お買い求めください！
so please check it out if you'd like!
素敵な曲に仕上がってますんで、よろしくお願いします。
It's turned out to be a wonderful song.
で、えっと、今週は私、えっと、
And, let's see, this week...
ラミィちゃん、ねねちゃん、私っていう順番で今やってるじゃないですか、
Lamy-chan, Nene-chan, and then me...
一周年記念。で、次ラスト、おまる、
we've been doing our 1st anniversaries in that order.
おまる・ポルカなんですけれども、
Next and last is Omaru Polka.
一旦明日は、えっとホロライブ公式の配信で、
But first, tomorrow, on the official Hololive channel,
「ホロライブ・エラー」が8時から放送予定となってますので、
"Hololive Error" is scheduled to broadcast at 8:00 PM,
そちらを見てもらってから、明後日、
so please watch that. Then, the day after tomorrow,
えっと16日の月曜日、えっとおまる・ポルカのね、記念配信がありますので、
on Monday the 16th, Polka will have her anniversary stream,
そちらも是非、8時からあるらしいので、チェックして見てください！
which starts at 8:00 PM, so please check it out!
はい、ありがとうございます。ちょっとお知らせ、駆け足気味にはなってますけど。
Thank you. I know those announcements were a bit rushed.
よかったら是非、記念グッズは多分もうカート開いてるかな？
The anniversary goods should be available in the cart now.
あるので、是非お買い求めいただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be really happy if you picked some up!
オリ曲もよろしくお願いします。
And please check out my original song too.
じゃあそうだね、
Well then,
今日はみんな本当に見てくれてありがとう。あの、
thank you all so much for watching today.
アイドル、今日はアイドルっていうテーマでね、やってきたんですけど、
I've been going with the theme "Today I'm an Idol,"
最後もちょっとね、頑張ってアイドルやるぞ！っていうことで、
and I'm going to give it my all as an idol until the very end!
よろしくお願いします。
Here we go.
それでは、最後の曲です。聴いてください。
And now, for the final song. Please listen.
「幽霊東京」。
"Yuurei Tokyo."
燦然と輝く街の灯
The city lights shine brilliantly,
対照的な僕を見下ろす
Looking down upon me in contrast.
あのビルの間を抜けて
Passing through those buildings,
色付きだした夜に混じって
Mixing into the night beginning to take color,
僕の時間はこの世界をトレード、夜に沈む
My time trades with this world, sinking into the night.
終電で家路を辿る僕の目に映る
Reflected in my eyes on the way home on the last train,
ガラス窓に居たのは夢見た自分じゃなくて
In the glass window was not the self I dreamed of.
今にも泣き出してしまいそうな
Looking like they could burst into tears at any moment,
暗闇の中独り彷徨っている、悲しい人
A sad person wandering alone in the darkness.
大丈夫、いつか大丈夫
It's okay, someday it'll be okay,
になるなんて思う日々を幾つか重ねた
So I thought as the days piled up.
今日だって独り東京の景色に...
Even today, alone in this Tokyo scenery...
怠惰的にさ
In a state of laziness...
絡まった誇りは幽霊みたいだ
the tangled dust is like a ghost.
失うことに慣れていくなかで
As I get used to losing things,
忘れてしまったあの願いさえも
even those wishes I've forgotten...
思い出した時に涙が落ちたのは
When I remembered them, the reason my tears fell
この街がただあまりにも眩しいから
is simply because this city is so dazzling.
散々だって笑いながら
Laughing about how terrible it is,
嘆く退廃的な日々のなかで
in the midst of lamenting decadent days,
あの日、想いがフラッシュバック
that day, my thoughts flashed back.
気づけば朝まで開くネガ
Before I knew it, I was looking at negatives until morning.
僕の言葉を音に乗せて何度でも
I'll put my words into sound, over and over again.
失うことに慣れていくなかで
As I get used to losing things,
忘れてしまったあの日々さえも
even those days I've forgotten...
それでもまた前を向けるのは
Even so, the reason I can look forward again
君がいるから
is because you're here.
ねえ
Hey...
こんな寂しい街で
In such a lonely city...
ねえ
Hey...
燦然と輝く街の灯り
The brilliantly shining city lights
対照的な僕を見下ろす
look down on me in contrast.
あのビルの先 手を伸ばして
Reaching out past that building,
あの日夢見た景色をなぞって
tracing the scenery I dreamed of that day,
僕の時間とこの世界をトレード
trading my time with this world,
明日を呼ぶ
calling for tomorrow.
失うことに慣れていくなかで
As I get used to losing things,
失くさずにいた大事な想いを
the precious feelings I managed to keep...
抱きしめたら不意に涙が落ちたのは
When I held them close, the reason my tears suddenly fell
この街でまだ
is because in this city, still,
生きていたいと思うから
I think I want to keep living.
君もそうでしょ
You feel the same, right?
みんな、今日はありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for today!
このあと21時15分から、オリジナル楽曲「Lioness' Pride」も、よかったら見てね！
After this, starting from 21:15, please check out my original song "Lioness' Pride" if you like!
またね！バイバイ！
See you! Bye-bye!